<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>YAB (Yet Another Blog)</title>
    <link>http://shalbhav.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on YAB (Yet Another Blog)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://shalbhav.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Monty Hall Problem: Intuition and Simulation</title>
      <link>http://shalbhav.github.io/posts/monty-hall-sim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://shalbhav.github.io/posts/monty-hall-sim/</guid>
      <description>The Monty Hall problem is an interesting puzzle in probability which has a counter-intuitive answer. In fact, it is documented that many well known mathematicians, PhDs and nobel laureates got the answer wrong too and many people continue to get the answer wrong.
The problem The problem goes somewhat like this:
Imagine a game show. There are 3 doors and behind one door there is a car and behind the other 2, goats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presenting with Emacs Org-mode</title>
      <link>http://shalbhav.github.io/posts/org-mode-present-focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://shalbhav.github.io/posts/org-mode-present-focus/</guid>
      <description>Emacs org-mode is an emacs major mode used for note keeping, project planning and for creating documents and articles. It has many export options from markdown to pdf to latex. While all this is great for document generation, it can also be used for creating presentations with org-reveal. Still, this needs a browser and sometimes you really have more text than a few bullet points and want a simpler option to just focus on the text under each heading by narrowing to each heading as you present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extending life of the Mosquito Bat</title>
      <link>http://shalbhav.github.io/posts/extend-life-mosquito-bat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://shalbhav.github.io/posts/extend-life-mosquito-bat/</guid>
      <description>Mosquito bats work great for killing mosquitoes and flies. Until they don&amp;rsquo;t work! They hardly last one mosquito generation. It turns out that the rechargeable battery in them go bad fairly quickly. So as a small hack, I took out the cheap battery they come with and replaced it with a decent rechargeable LiIon 3.7v 2200mah one. You have to modify the battery housing a little bit by carving out some extra bits of plastic to make the 18650 type battery to fit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A container does not need an OS</title>
      <link>http://shalbhav.github.io/posts/container-no-os/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://shalbhav.github.io/posts/container-no-os/</guid>
      <description>Apparently a container does not even need an OS whereas VMs do. Container != VM, but I never stopped to think about this before. Processes within the container can directly talk to the kernel on which the container is running. Most containers are built with a base OS image. Turns out you can create an image without a base OS by pulling the scratch image, that contains nothing.
Let&amp;rsquo;s create a small c program that is statically compiled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Kubernetes scaling using some Algebra</title>
      <link>http://shalbhav.github.io/posts/k8s-hpa-algebra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://shalbhav.github.io/posts/k8s-hpa-algebra/</guid>
      <description>Kubernetes Horizontal Pod Autoscaling provides a way to scale up number of Pod replicas in a deployment based on per-pod metric thresholds set by the operator. Most often the per-pod resource metrics (like CPU and memory) are used to scale the pods. The utilization value is computed over all the containers in each Pod.
Starting with v1.20, Kubernetes started offering HPA scaling based on container resource metrics as an alpha feature (as of the time of this writing).</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
